<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dynamic-Programming on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/dynamic-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dynamic-Programming on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:21:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/dynamic-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem 3259 Maximum Energy Boost From Two Drinks</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/contest_lc/problem-3259-maximum-energy-boost-from-two-drinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:21:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/contest_lc/problem-3259-maximum-energy-boost-from-two-drinks/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 3259 Question You are given two integer arrays energyDrinkA and energyDrinkB of the same length n by a futuristic sports scientist. These arrays represent the energy boosts per hour provided by two different energy drinks, A and B, respectively.&#xA;You want to maximize your total energy boost by drinking one energy drink per hour. However, if you want to switch from consuming one energy drink to the other, you need to wait for one hour to cleanse your system (meaning you won&amp;rsquo;t get any energy boost in that hour).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 55 Jump Game</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-55-jump-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:52:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-55-jump-game/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 55 Question You are given an integer array nums. You are initially positioned at the array&amp;rsquo;s first index, and each element in the array represents your maximum jump length at that position.&#xA;Return true if you can reach the last index, or false otherwise.&#xA;Example 1 Input: nums = [2,3,1,1,4] Output: true Explanation: Jump 1 step from index 0 to 1, then 3 steps to the last index.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 62 Unique Paths</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-62-unique-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 23:17:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-62-unique-paths/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 62 Question There is a robot on an m x n grid. The robot is initially located at the top-left corner (i.e., grid[0][0]). The robot tries to move to the bottom-right corner (i.e., grid[m - 1][n - 1]). The robot can only move either down or right at any point in time.&#xA;Given the two integers m and n, return the number of possible unique paths that the robot can take to reach the bottom-right corner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1395 Count Number of Teams</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-1395-count-number-of-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 18:30:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-1395-count-number-of-teams/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1395 Question There are n soldiers standing in a line. Each soldier is assigned a unique rating value.&#xA;You have to form a team of 3 soldiers amongst them under the following rules:&#xA;Choose 3 soldiers with index (i, j, k) with rating (rating[i], rating[j], rating[k]). A team is valid if: (rating[i] &amp;lt; rating[j] &amp;lt; rating[k]) or (rating[i] &amp;gt; rating[j] &amp;gt; rating[k]) where (0 &amp;lt;= i &amp;lt; j &amp;lt; k &amp;lt; n).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
