<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Binary-Search on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/binary-search/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Binary-Search on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 22:34:05 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/binary-search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem Intersection of Two Arrays II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-intersection-of-two-arrays-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 22:34:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-intersection-of-two-arrays-ii/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 350 Question Given two integer arrays nums1 and nums2, return an array of their intersection. Each element in the result must appear as many times as it shows in both arrays and you may return the result in any order.&#xA;Example 1 Input: nums1 = [1,2,2,1], nums2 = [2,2] Output: [2,2] Example 2 Input: nums1 = [4,9,5], nums2 = [9,4,9,8,4] Output: [4,9] Explanation: [9,4] is also accepted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Magnetic Force Between Two Balls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-magnetic-force-between-two-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 21:42:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-magnetic-force-between-two-balls/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1552 Question In the universe Earth C-137, Rick discovered a special form of magnetic force between two balls if they are put in his new invented basket. Rick has n empty baskets, the ith basket is at position[i], Morty has m balls and needs to distribute the balls into the baskets such that the minimum magnetic force between any two balls is maximum.&#xA;Rick stated that magnetic force between two different balls at positions x and y is |x - y|.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Minimum Number of Days to Make M Bouquets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-minimum-number-of-days-to-make-m-bouquets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 23:03:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-minimum-number-of-days-to-make-m-bouquets/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1482 Question You are given an integer array bloomDay, an integer m and an integer k.&#xA;You want to make m bouquets. To make a bouquet, you need to use k adjacent flowers from the garden.&#xA;The garden consists of n flowers, the ith flower will bloom in the bloomDay[i] and then can be used in exactly one bouquet.&#xA;Return the minimum number of days you need to wait to be able to make m bouquets from the garden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem K th Smallest Prime Fraction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-k-th-smallest-prime-fraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 19:04:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-k-th-smallest-prime-fraction/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 786 Question You are given a sorted integer array arr containing 1 and prime numbers, where all the integers of arr are unique. You are also given an integer k.&#xA;For every i and j where 0 &amp;lt;= i &amp;lt; j &amp;lt; arr.length, we consider the fraction arr[i] / arr[j].&#xA;Return the kth smallest fraction considered. Return your answer as an array of integers of size 2, where answer[0] == arr[i] and answer[1] == arr[j].</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
