<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matrix on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/matrix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matrix on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 23:19:57 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/matrix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem 54 Sprial Matrix</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-54-sprial-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 23:19:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-54-sprial-matrix/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 54 Question Given an m x n matrix, return all elements of the matrix in spiral order.&#xA;Example 1 Input: matrix = [[1,2,3],[4,5,6],[7,8,9]] Output: [1,2,3,6,9,8,7,4,5] Example 2 Input: matrix = [[1,2,3,4],[5,6,7,8],[9,10,11,12]] Output: [1,2,3,4,8,12,11,10,9,5,6,7] Constraints - `m == matrix.length` - `n == matrix[i].length` - `1 &amp;lt;= m, n &amp;lt;= 10` - `-100 &amp;lt;= matrix[i][j] &amp;lt;= 100` Solution class Solution { public: vector&amp;lt;int&amp;gt; spiralOrder(vector&amp;lt;vector&amp;lt;int&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;amp; matrix) { int rows = matrix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 832 Flipping an Image</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-832-flipping-an-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 21:38:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-832-flipping-an-image/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 832 Question Given an n x n binary matrix image, flip the image horizontally, then invert it, and return the resulting image.&#xA;To flip an image horizontally means that each row of the image is reversed.&#xA;For example, flipping [1,1,0] horizontally results in [0,1,1]. To invert an image means that each 0 is replaced by 1, and each 1 is replaced by 0.&#xA;For example, inverting [0,1,1] results in [1,0,0].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1605 Find Valid Matrix Given Row and Column Sums</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-1605-find-valid-matrix-given-row-and-column-sums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 21:18:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-1605-find-valid-matrix-given-row-and-column-sums/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1605 Question You are given two arrays rowSum and colSum of non-negative integers where rowSum[i] is the sum of the elements in the ith row and colSum[j] is the sum of the elements of the jth column of a 2D matrix. In other words, you do not know the elements of the matrix, but you do know the sums of each row and column.&#xA;Find any matrix of non-negative integers of size rowSum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1380 Lucky Number in a Matrix</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-lucky-number-in-a-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 21:38:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-lucky-number-in-a-matrix/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1380 Question Given an m x n matrix of distinct numbers, return all lucky numbers in the matrix in any order.&#xA;A lucky number is an element of the matrix such that it is the minimum element in its row and maximum in its column.&#xA;Example 1 Input: matrix = [[3,7,8],[9,11,13],[15,16,17]] Output: [15] Explanation: 15 is the only lucky number since it is the minimum in its row and the maximum in its column.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1219 Path With Maximum Gold</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-path-with-maximum-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 22:27:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-path-with-maximum-gold/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1219 Question In a gold mine grid of size m x n, each cell in this mine has an integer representing the amount of gold in that cell, 0 if it is empty.&#xA;Return the maximum amount of gold you can collect under the conditions:&#xA;Every time you are located in a cell you will collect all the gold in that cell. From your position, you can walk one step to the left, right, up, or down.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 861 Score After Flipping Matrix</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-score-after-flipping-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 20:20:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-score-after-flipping-matrix/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 861 Question You are given an m x n binary matrix grid.&#xA;A move consists of choosing any row or column and toggling each value in that row or column (i.e., changing all 0&amp;rsquo;s to 1&amp;rsquo;s, and all 1&amp;rsquo;s to 0&amp;rsquo;s).&#xA;Every row of the matrix is interpreted as a binary number, and the score of the matrix is the sum of these numbers.&#xA;Return the highest possible score after making any number of moves (including zero moves).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2373 Largest Local Values in a Matrix</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-largest-local-values-in-a-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 10:58:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-largest-local-values-in-a-matrix/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2373 Question You are given an n x n integer matrix grid.&#xA;Generate an integer matrix maxLocal of size (n - 2) x (n - 2) such that:&#xA;maxLocal[i][j] is equal to the largest value of the 3 x 3 matrix in grid centered around row i + 1 and column j + 1. In other words, we want to find the largest value in every contiguous 3 x 3 matrix in grid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1289 Minimum Falling Path Sum II</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-minimum-falling-path-sum-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:15:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-minimum-falling-path-sum-ii/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link: Problem 1289 Question Given an n x n integer matrix grid, return the minimum sum of a falling path with non-zero shifts.&#xA;A falling path with non-zero shifts is a choice of exactly one element from each row of grid such that no two elements chosen in adjacent rows are in the same column.&#xA;Example 1 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 Input: grid = [[1,2,3],[4,5,6],[7,8,9]] Output: 13 Explanation: The possible falling paths are: [1,5,9], [1,5,7], [1,6,7], [1,6,8], [2,4,8], [2,4,9], [2,6,7], [2,6,8], [3,4,8], [3,4,9], [3,5,7], [3,5,9] The falling path with the smallest sum is [1,5,7], so the answer is 13.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1992 Find All Groups of Farmland</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-find-all-groups-of-farmland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 10:52:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-find-all-groups-of-farmland/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1992 Question You are given a 0-indexed m x n binary matrix land where a 0 represents a hectare of forested land and a 1 represents a hectare of farmland.&#xA;To keep the land organized, there are designated rectangular areas of hectares that consist entirely of farmland. These rectangular areas are called groups. No two groups are adjacent, meaning farmland in one group is not four-directionally adjacent to another farmland in a different group.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 200 Number of Islands</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-number-of-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 13:00:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-number-of-islands/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 200 Question Given an m x n 2D binary grid grid which represents a map of &#39;1&#39;s (land) and &#39;0&#39;s (water), return the number of islands.&#xA;An island is surrounded by water and is formed by connecting adjacent lands horizontally or vertically. You may assume all four edges of the grid are all surrounded by water.&#xA;Note to self They use characters not integers for 1 and 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 463 Island Perimeter</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-island-perimeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:48:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-island-perimeter/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 463 Question You are given row x col grid representing a map where grid[i][j] = 1 represents land and grid[i][j] = 0 represents water.&#xA;Grid cells are connected horizontally/vertically (not diagonally). The grid is completely surrounded by water, and there is exactly one island (i.e., one or more connected land cells).&#xA;The island doesn&amp;rsquo;t have &amp;ldquo;lakes&amp;rdquo;, meaning the water inside isn&amp;rsquo;t connected to the water around the island.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
