<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graph on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/graph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graph on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 18:56:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/graph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem 787 Cheapest Flights Within K Stops</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-787-cheapest-flights-within-k-stops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 18:56:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-787-cheapest-flights-within-k-stops/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 787 Question There are n cities connected by some number of flights. You are given an array flights where flights[i] = [fromi, toi, pricei] indicates that there is a flight from city fromi to city toi with cost pricei.&#xA;You are also given three integers src, dst, and k, return the cheapest price from src to dst with at most k stops. If there is no such route, return -1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 743 Network Delay Time</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-743-network-delay-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 18:41:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/extraques/problem-743-network-delay-time/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 743 Question You are given a network of n nodes, labeled from 1 to n. You are also given times, a list of travel times as directed edges times[i] = (ui, vi, wi), where ui is the source node, vi is the target node, and wi is the time it takes for a signal to travel from source to target.&#xA;We will send a signal from a given node k.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2976 Minimum Cost to Convert String I</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-2976-minimum-cost-to-convert-string-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:35:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-2976-minimum-cost-to-convert-string-i/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem Question You are given two 0-indexed strings source and target, both of length n and consisting of lowercase English letters. You are also given two 0-indexed character arrays original and changed, and an integer array cost, where cost[i] represents the cost of changing the character original[i] to the character changed[i].&#xA;You start with the string source. In one operation, you can pick a character x from the string and change it to the character y at a cost of z if there exists any index j such that cost[j] == z, original[j] == x, and changed[j] == y.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2192 All Ancestors of a Node in a DAG</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-all-ancestors-of-a-node-in-a-dag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 10:39:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-all-ancestors-of-a-node-in-a-dag/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2192 Question You are given a positive integer n representing the number of nodes of a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG). The nodes are numbered from 0 to n - 1 (inclusive).&#xA;You are also given a 2D integer array edges, where edges[i] = [fromi, toi] denotes that there is a unidirectional edge from fromi to toi in the graph.&#xA;Return a list answer, where answer[i] is the list of ancestors of the ith node, sorted in ascending order.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2285 Maximum Total Importance of Roads</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-maximum-total-importance-of-roads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:39:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-maximum-total-importance-of-roads/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2285 Question You are given an integer n denoting the number of cities in a country. The cities are numbered from 0 to n - 1.&#xA;You are also given a 2D integer array roads where roads[i] = [ai, bi] denotes that there exists a bidirectional road connecting cities ai and bi.&#xA;You need to assign each city with an integer value from 1 to n, where each value can only be used once.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1791 Find Center of Star Graph</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-find-center-of-star-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:59:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-find-center-of-star-graph/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1791 Question There is an undirected star graph consisting of n nodes labeled from 1 to n. A star graph is a graph where there is one center node and exactly n - 1 edges that connect the center node with every other node.&#xA;You are given a 2D integer array edges where each edges[i] = [ui, vi] indicates that there is an edge between the nodes ui and vi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 752 Open the Lock</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-open-the-lock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 16:27:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-open-the-lock/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 752 Question You have a lock in front of you with 4 circular wheels. Each wheel has 10 slots: &#39;0&#39;, &#39;1&#39;, &#39;2&#39;, &#39;3&#39;, &#39;4&#39;, &#39;5&#39;, &#39;6&#39;, &#39;7&#39;, &#39;8&#39;, &#39;9&#39;. The wheels can rotate freely and wrap around: for example we can turn &#39;9&#39; to be &#39;0&#39;, or &#39;0&#39; to be &#39;9&#39;. Each move consists of turning one wheel one slot.&#xA;The lock initially starts at &#39;0000&#39;, a string representing the state of the 4 wheels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1971 Find if Path Exists in Graph</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-find-if-path-exists-in-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:42:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-find-if-path-exists-in-graph/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1971 Question There is a bi-directional graph with n vertices, where each vertex is labeled from 0 to n-1 (inclusive). The edges in the graph are represented as a 2D integer array edges, where each edges[i] = [ui, vi] denotes a bi-directional edge between vertex ui and vertex vi. Every vertex pair is connected by at most one edge, and no vertex has an edge to itself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
