<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graph on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/graph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graph on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 10:39:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/graph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem All Ancestors of a Node in a DAG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-all-ancestors-of-a-node-in-a-dag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 10:39:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-all-ancestors-of-a-node-in-a-dag/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2192 Question You are given a positive integer n representing the number of nodes of a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG). The nodes are numbered from 0 to n - 1 (inclusive).&#xA;You are also given a 2D integer array edges, where edges[i] = [fromi, toi] denotes that there is a unidirectional edge from fromi to toi in the graph.&#xA;Return a list answer, where answer[i] is the list of ancestors of the ith node, sorted in ascending order.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Maximum Total Importance of Roads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-maximum-total-importance-of-roads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:39:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-maximum-total-importance-of-roads/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2285 Question You are given an integer n denoting the number of cities in a country. The cities are numbered from 0 to n - 1.&#xA;You are also given a 2D integer array roads where roads[i] = [ai, bi] denotes that there exists a bidirectional road connecting cities ai and bi.&#xA;You need to assign each city with an integer value from 1 to n, where each value can only be used once.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Find Center of Star Graph</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-find-center-of-star-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 10:59:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-find-center-of-star-graph/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1791 Question There is an undirected star graph consisting of n nodes labeled from 1 to n. A star graph is a graph where there is one center node and exactly n - 1 edges that connect the center node with every other node.&#xA;You are given a 2D integer array edges where each edges[i] = [ui, vi] indicates that there is an edge between the nodes ui and vi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Open the Lock</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-open-the-lock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 16:27:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-open-the-lock/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 752 Question You have a lock in front of you with 4 circular wheels. Each wheel has 10 slots: &#39;0&#39;, &#39;1&#39;, &#39;2&#39;, &#39;3&#39;, &#39;4&#39;, &#39;5&#39;, &#39;6&#39;, &#39;7&#39;, &#39;8&#39;, &#39;9&#39;. The wheels can rotate freely and wrap around: for example we can turn &#39;9&#39; to be &#39;0&#39;, or &#39;0&#39; to be &#39;9&#39;. Each move consists of turning one wheel one slot.&#xA;The lock initially starts at &#39;0000&#39;, a string representing the state of the 4 wheels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Find if Path Exists in Graph</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-find-if-path-exists-in-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:42:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/problem-find-if-path-exists-in-graph/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1971 Question There is a bi-directional graph with n vertices, where each vertex is labeled from 0 to n-1 (inclusive). The edges in the graph are represented as a 2D integer array edges, where each edges[i] = [ui, vi] denotes a bi-directional edge between vertex ui and vertex vi. Every vertex pair is connected by at most one edge, and no vertex has an edge to itself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
