<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vectors on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/vectors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vectors on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 18:30:07 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/vectors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1395 Count Number of Teams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-1395-count-number-of-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 18:30:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-1395-count-number-of-teams/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1395 Question There are n soldiers standing in a line. Each soldier is assigned a unique rating value.&#xA;You have to form a team of 3 soldiers amongst them under the following rules:&#xA;Choose 3 soldiers with index (i, j, k) with rating (rating[i], rating[j], rating[k]). A team is valid if: (rating[i] &amp;lt; rating[j] &amp;lt; rating[k]) or (rating[i] &amp;gt; rating[j] &amp;gt; rating[k]) where (0 &amp;lt;= i &amp;lt; j &amp;lt; k &amp;lt; n).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2191 Sort the Jumbled Number</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-2191-sort-the-jumbled-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 21:58:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-2191-sort-the-jumbled-number/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2191 Question You are given a 0-indexed integer array mapping which represents the mapping rule of a shuffled decimal system. mapping[i] = j means digit i should be mapped to digit j in this system.&#xA;The mapped value of an integer is the new integer obtained by replacing each occurrence of digit i in the integer with mapping[i] for all 0 &amp;lt;= i &amp;lt;= 9.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 136 Single Number</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-single-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 21:33:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-single-number/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 136 Question Given a non-empty array of integers nums, every element appears twice except for one. Find that single one.&#xA;You must implement a solution with a linear runtime complexity and use only constant extra space.&#xA;Note We need O(1) space and O(n) time complexity. That means we cant use any other space to store frequency of elements and cant sort the array and check for the element which is not repeated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1051 Height Checker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-height-checker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 21:19:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-height-checker/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1051 Question A school is trying to take an annual photo of all the students. The students are asked to stand in a single file line in non-decreasing order by height. Let this ordering be represented by the integer array expected where expected[i] is the expected height of the ith student in line.&#xA;You are given an integer array heights representing the current order that the students are standing in.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
