<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greedy on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/greedy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greedy on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:40:45 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/greedy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem Minimum Difference Between Largest and Smallest Value in Three Moves</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-minimum-difference-between-largest-and-smallest-value-in-three-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 21:40:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-minimum-difference-between-largest-and-smallest-value-in-three-moves/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1509 Question You are given an integer array nums.&#xA;In one move, you can choose one element of nums and change it to any value.&#xA;Return the minimum difference between the largest and smallest value of nums after performing at most three moves&#xA;Example 1 Input: nums = [5,3,2,4] Output: 0 Explanation: We can make at most 3 moves. In the first move, change 2 to 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Most Profit Assigning Work</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-most-profit-assigning-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 20:52:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-most-profit-assigning-work/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 826 Question You have n jobs and m workers. You are given three arrays: difficulty, profit, and worker where:&#xA;difficulty[i] and profit[i] are the difficulty and the profit of the ith job, and&#xA;worker[j] is the ability of jth worker (i.e., the jth worker can only complete a job with difficulty at most worker[j]). Every worker can be assigned at most one job, but one job can be completed multiple times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem IPO</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-ipo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 10:35:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-ipo/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 502 Question Suppose LeetCode will start its IPO soon. In order to sell a good price of its shares to Venture Capital, LeetCode would like to work on some projects to increase its capital before the IPO. Since it has limited resources, it can only finish at most k distinct projects before the IPO. Help LeetCode design the best way to maximize its total capital after finishing at most k distinct projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Minimum Increment to Make Array Unique</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-minimum-increment-to-make-array-unique/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 21:23:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-minimum-increment-to-make-array-unique/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 945 Question You are given an integer array nums. In one move, you can pick an index i where 0 &amp;lt;= i &amp;lt; nums.length and increment nums[i] by 1.&#xA;Return the minimum number of moves to make every value in nums unique.&#xA;The test cases are generated so that the answer fits in a 32-bit integer.&#xA;Example 1 Input: nums = [1,2,2] Output: 1 Explanation: After 1 move, the array could be [1, 2, 3].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Minimum Number of Moves to Seat Everyone</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-minimum-number-of-moves-to-seat-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 21:56:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-minimum-number-of-moves-to-seat-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2037 Question There are n seats and n students in a room. You are given an array seats of length n, where seats[i] is the position of the ith seat. You are also given the array students of length n, where students[j] is the position of the jth student.&#xA;You may perform the following move any number of times:&#xA;Increase or decrease the position of the ith student by 1 (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Hand of Straights</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-hand-of-straights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 23:33:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-hand-of-straights/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 846 Question Alice has some number of cards and she wants to rearrange the cards into groups so that each group is of size groupSize, and consists of groupSize consecutive cards.&#xA;Given an integer array hand where hand[i] is the value written on the ith card and an integer groupSize, return true if she can rearrange the cards, or false otherwise.&#xA;Note : Only groupSize matters not the number of groups.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Find the Maximum Sum of Node Values</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-find-the-maximum-sum-of-node-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 10:30:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-find-the-maximum-sum-of-node-values/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 3068 Question There exists an undirected tree with n nodes numbered 0 to n - 1. You are given a 0-indexed 2D integer array edges of length n - 1, where edges[i] = [ui, vi] indicates that there is an edge between nodes ui and vi in the tree. You are also given a positive integer k, and a 0-indexed array of non-negative integers nums of length n, where nums[i] represents the value of the node numbered i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Score After Flipping Matrix</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-score-after-flipping-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 20:20:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-score-after-flipping-matrix/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 861 Question You are given an m x n binary matrix grid.&#xA;A move consists of choosing any row or column and toggling each value in that row or column (i.e., changing all 0&amp;rsquo;s to 1&amp;rsquo;s, and all 1&amp;rsquo;s to 0&amp;rsquo;s).&#xA;Every row of the matrix is interpreted as a binary number, and the score of the matrix is the sum of these numbers.&#xA;Return the highest possible score after making any number of moves (including zero moves).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Maximize Happiness of Selected Children</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-maximize-happiness-of-selected-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 14:35:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-maximize-happiness-of-selected-children/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 3075 Question You are given an array happiness of length n, and a positive integer k.&#xA;There are n children standing in a queue, where the ith child has happiness value happiness[i]. You want to select k children from these n children in k turns.&#xA;In each turn, when you select a child, the happiness value of all the children that have not been selected till now decreases by 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem Boats to Save People</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-boats-to-save-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 15:00:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/problem-boats-to-save-people/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 881 Question You are given an array people where people[i] is the weight of the ith person, and an infinite number of boats where each boat can carry a maximum weight of limit. Each boat carries at most two people at the same time, provided the sum of the weight of those people is at most limit.&#xA;Return the minimum number of boats to carry every given person.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
