<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All-Pair-Shortest-Path on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/all-pair-shortest-path/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All-Pair-Shortest-Path on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:35:56 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/tags/all-pair-shortest-path/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2976 Minimum Cost to Convert String I</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-2976-minimum-cost-to-convert-string-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:35:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-2976-minimum-cost-to-convert-string-i/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem Question You are given two 0-indexed strings source and target, both of length n and consisting of lowercase English letters. You are also given two 0-indexed character arrays original and changed, and an integer array cost, where cost[i] represents the cost of changing the character original[i] to the character changed[i].&#xA;You start with the string source. In one operation, you can pick a character x from the string and change it to the character y at a cost of z if there exists any index j such that cost[j] == z, original[j] == x, and changed[j] == y.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1334 Find the City With the Smallest Number of Neighbours at a Threshold Distance</title>
      <link>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-1334-find-the-city-with-the-smallest-number-of-neighbours-at-a-threshold-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:00:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KTS-o7.github.io/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-1334-find-the-city-with-the-smallest-number-of-neighbours-at-a-threshold-distance/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1334 Question There are n cities numbered from 0 to n-1. Given the array edges where edges[i] = [fromi, toi, weighti] represents a bidirectional and weighted edge between cities fromi and toi, and given the integer distanceThreshold.&#xA;Return the city with the smallest number of cities that are reachable through some path and whose distance is at most distanceThreshold, If there are multiple such cities, return the city with the greatest number.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
