<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Array on KTS Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/array/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Array on KTS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Krishnatejaswi S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 23:19:57 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/array/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem 54 Sprial Matrix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/extraques/problem-54-sprial-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 23:19:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/extraques/problem-54-sprial-matrix/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 54 Question Given an m x n matrix, return all elements of the matrix in spiral order.&#xA;Example 1 Input: matrix = [[1,2,3],[4,5,6],[7,8,9]] Output: [1,2,3,6,9,8,7,4,5] Example 2 Input: matrix = [[1,2,3,4],[5,6,7,8],[9,10,11,12]] Output: [1,2,3,4,8,12,11,10,9,5,6,7] Constraints - `m == matrix.length` - `n == matrix[i].length` - `1 &amp;lt;= m, n &amp;lt;= 10` - `-100 &amp;lt;= matrix[i][j] &amp;lt;= 100` Solution class Solution { public: vector&amp;lt;int&amp;gt; spiralOrder(vector&amp;lt;vector&amp;lt;int&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;amp; matrix) { int rows = matrix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 624 Maximum Distance in Arrays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-624-maximum-distance-in-arrays/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 19:52:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-624-maximum-distance-in-arrays/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 624 Question You are given m arrays, where each array is sorted in ascending order.&#xA;You can pick up two integers from two different arrays (each array picks one) and calculate the distance. We define the distance between two integers a and b to be their absolute difference |a - b|.&#xA;Return the maximum distance.&#xA;Note Even though the dont mention in the problem statement, the integers a and b CANT be from the same array.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 860 Lemonade Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-860-lemonade-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 18:20:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-860-lemonade-change/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 860 Question At a lemonade stand, each lemonade costs $5. Customers are standing in a queue to buy from you and order one at a time (in the order specified by bills). Each customer will only buy one lemonade and pay with either a $5, $10, or $20 bill. You must provide the correct change to each customer so that the net transaction is that the customer pays $5.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 40 Combination Sum II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-40-combination-sum-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 10:33:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/daily_lc/problem-40-combination-sum-ii/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 40 Question Given a collection of candidate numbers (candidates) and a target number (target), find all unique combinations in candidates where the candidate numbers sum to target.&#xA;Each number in candidates may only be used once in the combination.&#xA;Note: The solution set must not contain duplicate combinations.&#xA;Example 1 Input: candidates = [10,1,2,7,6,1,5], target = 8 Output: [ [1,1,6], [1,2,5], [1,7], [2,6] ] Example 2 Input: candidates = [2,5,2,1,2], target = 5 Output: [ [1,2,2], [5] ] Constraints - `1 &amp;lt;= candidates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 832 Flipping an Image</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/extraques/problem-832-flipping-an-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 21:38:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/extraques/problem-832-flipping-an-image/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 832 Question Given an n x n binary matrix image, flip the image horizontally, then invert it, and return the resulting image.&#xA;To flip an image horizontally means that each row of the image is reversed.&#xA;For example, flipping [1,1,0] horizontally results in [0,1,1]. To invert an image means that each 0 is replaced by 1, and each 1 is replaced by 0.&#xA;For example, inverting [0,1,1] results in [1,0,0].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2751 Robot Collisions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-robot-collisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-robot-collisions/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2751 Question There are n 1-indexed robots, each having a position on a line, health, and movement direction.&#xA;You are given 0-indexed integer arrays positions, healths, and a string directions (directions[i] is either &amp;lsquo;L&amp;rsquo; for left or &amp;lsquo;R&amp;rsquo; for right). All integers in positions are unique.&#xA;All robots start moving on the line simultaneously at the same speed in their given directions. If two robots ever share the same position while moving, they will collide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1701 Average Waiting Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-average-waiting-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 23:52:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-average-waiting-time/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1701 Question There is a restaurant with a single chef. You are given an array customers, where customers[i] = [arrivali, timei]:&#xA;- arrivali is the arrival time of the ith customer. The arrival times are sorted in non-decreasing order.&#xA;timei is the time needed to prepare the order of the ith customer. When a customer arrives, he gives the chef his order, and the chef starts preparing it once he is idle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1550 Three Consecutive Odds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-three-consecutive-odds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:55:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-three-consecutive-odds/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1550 Question Given an integer array arr, return true if there are three consecutive odd numbers in the array. Otherwise, return false.&#xA;Example 1 Input: arr = [2,6,4,1] Output: false Explanation: There are no three consecutive odds. Example 2 Input: arr = [1,2,34,3,4,5,7,23,12] Output: true Explanation: [5,7,23] are three consecutive odds. Constraints - `1 &amp;lt;= arr.length &amp;lt;= 1000` - `1 &amp;lt;= arr[i] &amp;lt;= 1000` Solution class Solution { public: bool threeConsecutiveOdds(vector&amp;lt;int&amp;gt;&amp;amp; arr) { if(arr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1552 Magnetic Force Between Two Balls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-magnetic-force-between-two-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 21:42:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-magnetic-force-between-two-balls/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1552 Question In the universe Earth C-137, Rick discovered a special form of magnetic force between two balls if they are put in his new invented basket. Rick has n empty baskets, the ith basket is at position[i], Morty has m balls and needs to distribute the balls into the baskets such that the minimum magnetic force between any two balls is maximum.&#xA;Rick stated that magnetic force between two different balls at positions x and y is |x - y|.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1482 Minimum Number of Days to Make M Bouquets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-minimum-number-of-days-to-make-m-bouquets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 23:03:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-minimum-number-of-days-to-make-m-bouquets/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1482 Question You are given an integer array bloomDay, an integer m and an integer k.&#xA;You want to make m bouquets. To make a bouquet, you need to use k adjacent flowers from the garden.&#xA;The garden consists of n flowers, the ith flower will bloom in the bloomDay[i] and then can be used in exactly one bouquet.&#xA;Return the minimum number of days you need to wait to be able to make m bouquets from the garden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 502 IPO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-ipo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 10:35:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-ipo/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 502 Question Suppose LeetCode will start its IPO soon. In order to sell a good price of its shares to Venture Capital, LeetCode would like to work on some projects to increase its capital before the IPO. Since it has limited resources, it can only finish at most k distinct projects before the IPO. Help LeetCode design the best way to maximize its total capital after finishing at most k distinct projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 945 Minimum Increment to Make Array Unique</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-minimum-increment-to-make-array-unique/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 21:23:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-minimum-increment-to-make-array-unique/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 945 Question You are given an integer array nums. In one move, you can pick an index i where 0 &amp;lt;= i &amp;lt; nums.length and increment nums[i] by 1.&#xA;Return the minimum number of moves to make every value in nums unique.&#xA;The test cases are generated so that the answer fits in a 32-bit integer.&#xA;Example 1 Input: nums = [1,2,2] Output: 1 Explanation: After 1 move, the array could be [1, 2, 3].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2037 Minimum Number of Moves to Seat Everyone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-minimum-number-of-moves-to-seat-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 21:56:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-minimum-number-of-moves-to-seat-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 2037 Question There are n seats and n students in a room. You are given an array seats of length n, where seats[i] is the position of the ith seat. You are also given the array students of length n, where students[j] is the position of the jth student.&#xA;You may perform the following move any number of times:&#xA;Increase or decrease the position of the ith student by 1 (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 75 Sort Colors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-sort-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 18:48:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-sort-colors/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 75 Question Given an array nums with n objects colored red, white, or blue, sort them in-place so that objects of the same color are adjacent, with the colors in the order red, white, and blue.&#xA;We will use the integers 0, 1, and 2 to represent the color red, white, and blue, respectively.&#xA;You must solve this problem without using the library&amp;rsquo;s sort function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1002 Find Common Characters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-find-common-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 23:34:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-find-common-characters/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 1002 Question Given a string array words, return an array of all characters that show up in all strings within the words (including duplicates). You may return the answer in any order.&#xA;Example 1 Input: words = [&amp;#34;bella&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;label&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;roller&amp;#34;] Output: [&amp;#34;e&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;l&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;l&amp;#34;] Example 2 Input: words = [&amp;#34;cool&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;lock&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;cook&amp;#34;] Output: [&amp;#34;c&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;o&amp;#34;] Constraints 1 &amp;lt;= words.length &amp;lt;= 100 1 &amp;lt;= words[i].length &amp;lt;= 100 words[i] consists of lowercase English letters. Solution class Solution { public: vector&amp;lt;string&amp;gt; commonChars(vector&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&amp;amp; words) { vector&amp;lt;int&amp;gt;baselineCount(26,0); string temp; for(int i =0;i&amp;lt;words[0].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 786 K th Smallest Prime Fraction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-k-th-smallest-prime-fraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 19:04:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-k-th-smallest-prime-fraction/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 786 Question You are given a sorted integer array arr containing 1 and prime numbers, where all the integers of arr are unique. You are also given an integer k.&#xA;For every i and j where 0 &amp;lt;= i &amp;lt; j &amp;lt; arr.length, we consider the fraction arr[i] / arr[j].&#xA;Return the kth smallest fraction considered. Return your answer as an array of integers of size 2, where answer[0] == arr[i] and answer[1] == arr[j].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 200 Number of Islands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-number-of-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 13:00:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-number-of-islands/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 200 Question Given an m x n 2D binary grid grid which represents a map of &#39;1&#39;s (land) and &#39;0&#39;s (water), return the number of islands.&#xA;An island is surrounded by water and is formed by connecting adjacent lands horizontally or vertically. You may assume all four edges of the grid are all surrounded by water.&#xA;Note to self They use characters not integers for 1 and 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem 463 Island Perimeter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-island-perimeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:48:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/prev_solns/problem-island-perimeter/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Link - Problem 463 Question You are given row x col grid representing a map where grid[i][j] = 1 represents land and grid[i][j] = 0 represents water.&#xA;Grid cells are connected horizontally/vertically (not diagonally). The grid is completely surrounded by water, and there is exactly one island (i.e., one or more connected land cells).&#xA;The island doesn&amp;rsquo;t have &amp;ldquo;lakes&amp;rdquo;, meaning the water inside isn&amp;rsquo;t connected to the water around the island.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
